Mert Paker

Data, DevOps and Cloud Consultant

I have a development and operations background specialised in data analytics products and pipelines. I am a Google Cloud Certified Associate Cloud Engineer. I have experience with Google Cloud Platform as a developer and as a DevOps engineer. I developed a backend for a mobile application, won one Cloud Hero and two Qwiklabs competitions on Google Cloud Platform.

mertpaker@gmail.com	\geq
+44 7340 872425	

London, United Kingdom

9

linkedin.com/in/mertpaker **in**

SKILLS



PERSONAL STARTUP PROJECT

Fithletic - An online, mobile marketplace for gym and sports services (02/2017 – 03/2018)

- Created an architecture on Firebase & Google Cloud Platform
- Developed the serverless backend (NodeJS/Python) with Google Cloud Functions and Datastore, monitored integrations with Stackdriver, created data pipelines with Dataflow, and created dashboards with Google Data Studio.
- Developed the iOS application

WORK EXPERIENCE

Platform Engineer

Turkcell

09/2016 – 03/2019 Turkey's Leader Mobile Operator

Achievements/Tasks

- Took responsibilities as a DevOps Engineer (maintaining and automating systems) and Data Engineer (building and managing data pipelines)
- Created and maintained Jenkins jobs/workflows to automate deployments, test environment creations (with Terraform) and other operational procedures
- Operated Apache Airflow systems, and created data pipelines with data quality checks
- Developed python applications and bash scripts for operational needs and ETL jobs
- Architected, installed and maintained an IoT system with NodeJS and Apache Kafka
- Monitored application performance with Dynatrace, Splunk and Prometheus
- Created Splunk and SQL queries and dashboards to monitor technical and business metrics
- Operated Operating Systems (Linux & Windows) and Relational (Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL) /NoSQL (MongoDB, CouchDB, Cassandra) databases
- Operated and maintained enterprise applications (served by Weblogic and Tomcat), web services (Apache, Nginx and Flask) and their integrations
- Was responsible for release management, capacity planning, software upgrade, patch rollout, performance tuning and security

Istanbul, Turkey

WORK EXPERIENCE

System Engineer

Avea, Turk Telekom

09/2011 – 09/2016 Istanbul, Turkey

The largest integrated telecom operator in Turkey

Achievements/Tasks

- Operated and maintained physical servers, operating systems (Linux and Windows), ETL applications and Oracle databases
- Organised and managed software integrations with vendors
- Ensured the availability of applications and services
- Formed SLAs and SLOs with internal customers and other technical stakeholders

Integration & Support Engineer

Innovile Telecommunications Ltd

10/2010 – 09/2011 A software company that provide solutions for the Telecom sector

Achievements/Tasks

- Created data lakes from exports (CSV, XML, JSON) and databases (Oracle, Sybase) of different Telecom vendors
- Created and maintained jobs within the ETL solution of the company

Software Engineer

Vestel Electronics

03/2008 – 10/2010
Home and professional appliances manufacturing company

Achievements/Tasks

- Developed embedded software for TV systems with C/C++
- Designed and developed UI and middleware components for a TV to use with iPod

EDUCATION

Master of Entrepreneurship (MA)

Ozyegin University

09/2012 – 09/2015 Istanbul, Turkey

Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering (BSc)

Istanbul Technical University

09/2000 – 08/2005 Istanbul, Turkey

COURSES & CERTIFICATES

Qwiklabs - Google Cloud Quests 🗗 Coursera - Architecting with Google Cloud

Platform 🗹

Coursera - Data Engineering on GCP 🗗 Udacity - Data Analyst Nanodegree 🗗

DataCamp - Data Scientist with Python 🗹 Oracle - Database 11g Administration

Oracle - WebLogic Server 12c Administration Udemy - Taming Big Data with Apache Spark and

Python

Udemy - AWS Certified Big Data Specialty 2019 Google Cloud Certified Associate Cloud Engineer

(07/2019 - 07/2021)

Izmir, Turkey